<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biomechanics on QUKO | Data solutions</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/biomechanics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biomechanics on QUKO | Data solutions</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 12:00:10 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/biomechanics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biomechanical Analysis of Propulsion in Paddle Sports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025.06.30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 12:00:10 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025.06.30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking biomechanical analysis by researchers A. Baudouin and D. Hawkins from the University of California, Davis, published in the British Journal of Sports Medicine, reveals the complex interplay of forces that determine performance in rowing. While this research focuses specifically on rowing, the fundamental principles of propulsion, drag, and power transfer apply equally to sprint kayaking and canoeing, making these insights valuable for all paddle sport athletes seeking to optimize their performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic Contributions in Sprint Kayaking: 500m vs 1000m Analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025.06.24/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 12:00:10 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2025.06.24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent groundbreaking research from the University of Rennes has provided crucial insights into the physiological demands of Olympic kayaking distances that could revolutionize how paddlers and rowers approach their training. A comprehensive study by Zouhal and colleagues, published in the Journal of Strength and Conditioning Research, examined the precise energy system contributions during 500-meter and 1000-meter flat water kayaking races using advanced field-based measurements with elite athletes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
